in this video I will show you how to
translate the small word document using
Omega T version for the document we want
to translate is this one it's in finish
and we will translate it into English
for that we will be able to use some
sample energy supplied in the form of an
excel sheet it has two columns one for
finished ribs and the other one for
english terms
finally we have the reference
translation memory available in the TMX
format and we would be able to add that
translation memory to our Omega T
project so let's switch to Omega T Omega
T is a java-based application so it's
available for Windows Mac and Linux here
we are using the latest version
available for windows at this time which
is 4.4 . when we will create a new
project so for that a select project new
and Omega T project is stored in the
folder so i will create a specific
folder for my project that i will call
showing top if I en and save Omega T
remembered the language is our last used
so the source language is finish and
target languages British English Omega T
also created a number of sub folders
under my project folder there's 14
source documents when for translation
memories went for glossary and so on
click on OK now since i haven't selected
any translatable document yet that will
do it now so i click on copy files to
source folder and i will point to the
Omega T folder which is on my desktop
and this is the word document i want to
translate okay close the screen before i
continue i'll also open in windows
explorer my Omega T folder so it's
located here and project four days this
one and here I'll open the team folder
and this is where i will copy the TMX
processor memory that i mentioned
earlier so I will drag and drop it here
and I'm done next
first I have a glossary folder and this
is where Omega T expects its time energy
to be stored in so I'll go back to XM
and here since Omega T cannot use Excel
directly i will save this five save as
and i will select as the file type
unicode text so i will get a
tab-delimited file or make it expects
that five to be called glossary so and
change the name to grocery and I have to
store it in my Omega T order and mysore
dog project folder and the glossary
subfolder here now can close this five
and i have my glossary file in the
grocery order so now I'm ready for the
translation the first translatable
segment is put in bold by Omega T and
it's worth for highlighted in green by
default Omega T complicates the short
segments into the target segment since I
don't want this default behavior i'll go
to options and editor and here instead
of the source text i'll select leave the
segment empty so from now the target
segment will be left empty now i can
delete the content of the target segment
and I can enter my own translation so
nine passes Alcorn in English it's
getting started when my segment is ready
and I can move to the next 1i can use
the go to next
untranslatable segment common its
cultural you so now my second segment is
empty i can see in the grocery pain on
the lower right part of the Omega T
window that i have two terms that we're
recognized by Nick a button and Valley
core menu this terms were recognized
although they do not occur in exactly
the same form in my source segments or
communicate its nominative floor or a
spiny case nominative singular and same
with Valley good in order to enter these
recognize terms i can use the
autocomplete comments okay
press ctrl space and the glossary
entries will be on display here so the
first one is button I can accept it and
put it in Quran and yeah initiates and
for the third word i can again price
control space and i can select menu and
press enter
I put it in Quran and I can capitalize
the first word now I'm radio can press
ctrl you to move to the next segment
this is a long segment that has also won
recognized him in the same that we had
before
IDK button but this time it's finally
get that so it's the positive singular
but yet it was recognized by quickly
enter my translation and I can move to
the next segment with controller you
here again i have to recognize terms by
now price to $MONEY and a lot of alico
start menu so i can insert them with
again control space so the first one and
my conversation and electrical waves
Start menus or control space and enter
now I can move to the next segment again
with control you again to recognize
terms so controlled space and the rest
of the constellation and the last word
was menus for color space and menu next
segment control you again recognized him
by not so controlled space can copy it
and then rest cyclization and now this
word test hello I'm not sure but its
meaning so i would like to perform a
concurrent search there is no if I look
in the menu edit or go to or if I right
click on the word i can find anything
that points to conquer and search but
don't go to church in a magnitude simply
find which is ctrl f so if I not press
ctrl f Omega T will search for this word
in not only the memory but also the
groceries so i click on search and
indeed here i have a number of hits from
my BMX translation memory so i can see
that toaster below appears to be back
light
so i can select backlights there is no
specific comment for inserting that term
into the target signal so i can press
ctrl-c to copy it
I'll can close this display and i can
insert my term with ctrl v here so
backlight now if I want to add this new
term pair has developed backlight to my
grocery i can select the source term and
the Edit menu I can select create
glossary entry which is also control
shift g
now i have an entry form now can select
the corresponding target terms so
backlight and i can press again ctrl
shift g and now i can press ok and this
time pair will be inserted and indeed it
appears in the grocery pain right away
now can move to the next segment with
control you here i have a fuzzy match
actually I have 250 matches but the best
one is on top number one but make it
actually gives three different scores
for 50 matches so here this particular
matches either 66 or 71 or 84 person
depending on how you calculate it so
whereas most other catchers only give a
single score Omega T gives you three
they are acquainted in a manual and this
just shows that calculating pretty much
is not an exact science so it depends on
the tool that you use and even within
the same tool on the method that you use
for calculating night I want to insert
this match the selected match i can use
the Edit comment and insert match which
is control
I there are two differences between the
segment I now need to translate and when
that was positive previously the first
one before i had soared and taxi
increase now I have . taxi which is
decrease so I have to fix this
the second chance was private previously
I had english band which is up and now i
have alice band which is down so I to
make this change here and now my pretty
much has been corrected so I can move to
the next segment with control you again
when recognized terms so controlled
space i can insert it type the rest of
the translation and in this particular
segment there are two tags which
indicates the fact that this portion of
text here was in italic in the original
document so i need to insert the same
tags around the corresponding portion of
text here for that i can either use
control space
and then select the tag need and then
move to the end and press again control
space and insert the missing time or i
can select the portion of text that will
be enclosed between tags and i can press
ctrl space and I have both tags that can
be inserted at the same time now my
transition is ready so i can it
generates the target version of the
document for that
select project and save translated
documents which is ctrl D so if i go to
Windows Explorer and go to documents and
Omega T and my project folder and the
target folder i should find my trusted
document so if i open it it's in English
and it looks like everything is ok
including the formatting that we applied
the tags so there you have it
how to trust ate a small word document
using negative version for Thank You
fortune to subscribe to my channel for
more similar content also hit the like
button if you found this video useful to
use comments below this video if you
have any questions or feedback and see
you in the next one